Inventory of the Robert Morton Hughes Papers 1715-1933
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Personal and business correspondence, 1871-1933, n.d. (Box-folder 1:1-4)
  - Personal and Business Correspondence, 1911-1933, n.d., 19 items. (Box-folder 1:4)
    - E. Lee Trinkle, Governor of Virginia, Richmond, [Virginia], to R. M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 26 September 1925., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Thanks Hughes personally and officially for his "liberal treatment of the College of William and Mary."
    - F. Maurice, [London, England], to R. M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 25 November 1925., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Has completed his lectures on "Statesmen and Soldiers of the American Civil War" at Cambridge.
    - Gilbert Grosvenor, Washington, D.C., to Judge [sic] [Robert Morton] Hughes, n.p., 10 June 1930., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Concerning high honor conferred on him by the College of William and Mary.
    - Eleanor Roosevelt, The White House, Washington, [D.C.], to [Robert M.] Hughes, [Norfolk, Virginia], 12 October 1933., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Thanks Hughes for his letter and the information concerning Mr. [?] Sargeant.
    - John Lowell, Boston, [Massachusetts], to Robert M. Hughes, n.p., no date., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Concerns articles on the relief of the Supreme Court published in The Independent.
    - Waller R. Staples, Wytheville [Virginia], to [Robert M.] Hughes, n.p., 18 June n.y., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Inquiry into acts governing the harbor masters of Norfolk and Portsmouth, [Virginia].
  Series 2: Autograph Collection
- Autograph Collection, 1750-1933. (Box-folder 2:1-5)
  - Autograph Collection, A-C, 1750-1892., 19 items. (Box-folder 2:1)
    - J. Q. Adams, Washington, [D.C.], to John B. Davis, Boston, [Massachusetts], 29 January 1830., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Concerns the political situation in Massachusetts and the nation.
    - S. Adams, Governor of Massachusetts, Boston, [Massachusetts], to Thomas Davis, Treasurer, n.p., 21 June 1794., 1 page. DS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Order to pay 19.8.2 pounds to the heirs of Charles Anthony, deceased, late a private in Col. Bradford's Regiment, to make good the depreciation of his wages to the time of his death.
      Including ANS onverso. Receipt of James Sproat, n.p., 21 June 1794. 1 page.
    - Thomas Atkinson, Edenton, [North Carolina], to Mrs. [?] Sharpe, [Norfolk, Virginia?], 16 March 1857., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Concerns recent visit with Mr. and Mrs. Sharpe at Norfolk, [Virginia].
    - Receipt of W[illia]m Bowlegs, Fort Myers, [Florida?] from Lt. Colonel John H. Winder, 11 February 1852., 2 pages. Cy of DS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      for $90.00 for "searching for, finding, attending on, feeding, and bringing into Fort Myers" a drummer boy who was lost for eight days.
      Witnessed by W[illia]m H. French, Capt. 1st Art[illery] Br[e]v[e]t Major, and S.F. Chalfin, 1st Lt., 1st Art[iller]y
    - John C. Breckinbridge, Magee, Ontario, [Canada], to Gen. J[ubal] A. Early, Drummondville, Ontario, [Canada], 6 December 18[68]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Wants to get together; describes itinerary for the rest of the month; tells of a gallon of whiskey sent by Jno. Rankins, and his enjoyment thereof.
    - John A. Broadus, Louisville, Kentucky, to Miss Ella [?], n.p., 21 November [18]68., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Declines an invitation for his daughter, Ella, to visit "Miss Ella" because she must return to Miss Belle [Pears'] school.
    - N. F. Chairs, Major, 3rd Tennessee Regiment, CSA, and James W. Hewitt, Major, 2nd Kentucky Reg[imen]t, CSA, Russellville, Kentucky, to Brig. Gen. S.B. Buckner, CSA, n.p., 30 January 1862., 4 pages. LS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Order to and report of Board of Survey concerning damages done to Long's property by Confederate troops.
      Including an AD, by [N. Long] and endorsement by Buckner, n.d., estimating damages done to Long's factory, field, and farm. 2 pages.
    - Frances Hodgson Burnett, Washington, [D.C.], n.d., 1 item. Signature. (Box-folder 2:1)
    - A[aron] Burr, Albany, [New York], to Abraham Van Horne, n.p., 28 January 1783., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Concerning suits against Solomon Lathrop.
    - Jo[h]n C. Calhoun, Norfolk, [Virginia], to W. W. Sharp and H. B. Gwathney, Norfolk, [Virginia], 8 March 1835., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Declining an invitation and commenting on power and corruption.
    - Simon Cameron, Harrisburg, [Pennsylvania], to [F.T. Burr?], n.p., 24 December 1880., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Glad Burr will go South with him; will leave soon after the Senatorial election.
    - David Campbell, Governor of Virginia, Richmond, [Virginia], to The Executive authority of the State of New York, 1 May 1839., 1 page. DS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Warrant for return of a fugitive, Alexander Bogart, alias Alexander Bogart McCloed, to Edward N. Allen, agent of the Commonwealth. Signed also by Jno. B. Richardson, Assistant Secretary of the Commonwealth.
    - T. Campbell, Sydenham, [England], to J. Ogilvy, Covent Garden, [London, England], 10 August 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Hopes Ogilvy found the book "of which the missing has caused me the most poignant uneasiness."
    - Edw[ard] Canby, Richmond, [Virginia], to [?], 21 March [18]70., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Gives the full title of the case in South Carolina referred to in his notes.
    - R. Choate, n.p., to C. D. Boutelle[?], Washington, [D.C.], 14 February [1844]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Requests that Boutelle stop by his lodging as it is important to see him.
    - H. Clay, [Washington, D.C.], to B. Tucker, Williamsburg, Virginia, 29 December [1839]., 1 item. Franked envelope. (Box-folder 2:1)
    - Grover Cleveland, Gray Gables, Buzzards Bay, Massachusetts, to James Lyons, n.p., 14 July 1892., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Gratified to receive Lyons' letter, and expresses his exasperation if a victory were lost due to internal dissention or lack of hearty cooperation [referring to his third presidential campaign].
    - J. Esten Cooke, The Briars, [Virginia], to Mrs. Sal D. Duval, n.p., September 1875., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Concerning the health of [his wife] Mary, Robbie, and Cooke's own hay fever; the progress of his writings of the Revolution; comments on the pain of growing old and his love for Sister Mary and Overton.
    - [Lord] Cornbury, n.p., to Mr. Vice-Chancellor, Oxford University, England, [ca. 1750]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1)
      Concerning his unsolicited appointment as a Representative of the University in Parliament, his duties and responsibilities there, and his resignation upon being called up to the House of Lords.
  - Autograph Collection, D-H, 1715-1912., 33 items. (Box-folder 2:2)
    - Robert Dinwiddie, n.p., to Col. John Buchanan, n.p., no date., 2 pages. Fragment of LS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Requests that certain work be done in the army - pay the officers, report on the absence of men from their duties.
    - Check on Riggs & Co., made payable to "self", signed, S. A. Douglas, 22 December 1856., 1 page. DS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    - R. W. Emerson, Concord, Massachusetts, to Messrs. W.S. Perry, Alfred P. Thom, W. P. [sic] [R] McKenney, Committee, n.p., 21 December [18]75., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Accepts tentatively an invitation to visit two literary societies at the University of Virginia.
    - Eugene of Savoy, Prince, 11 December 1715., 1 page.. DS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Authorization for payment. In Italian.
    - R. S. Ewell, Lt. G[eneral], "H[ea]d Q[uarte]r[s], 2d Corps," to Gen. R. E. Lee, n.p., [July 1863?]. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Concerning momentary military situation near Hagerstown, [Maryland].
    - Francis Fauquier, Williamsburg, [Virginia], to James Kempe [and 16 others] of Princess Ann County, 21 March 1765., 1 page. PDS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Appointment as Justices of Oyer and Terminer for the felony trial of Stepney, a Negro slave belonging to Robert Ballard.
    - Millard Fillmore, Washington, [D.C.], to George Law, N[ew] York, [New York], 14 January 1851., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Acknowledges his election as an honorary member of the New York Rhetorical Society.
    - J. Floyd, n.p., to John Bowyer, Lexington, Virginia, no date., 1 item. Franked envelope. (Box-folder 2:2)
    - F[rederich the Great], Berlin, [Germany], to [?], 7 February 1740., 2 pages. LS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Regarding the Finor Canal. In German.
    - J.A. Froude, Crogen House, Corwen, N[orth] Wales, to [?], 12 June n.y., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Mentions that he [Froude] will be in Oxford on the 30th for the Exeter Gaudy; also a comment concerning a manuscript which was not allowed to be removed from the Bodleian.
    - J.A. Garfield, House of Representatives, Washington, D.C., to Edw[ard] G. Falmestock, W.T. Ziegler, and L. N. Barber, Gettysburgh [sic], Pennsylvania, 3 March 1880., 1 page. LS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Declines invitation to speak at Gettysburg on Decoration Day.
    - B.L. Gildersleeve, Baltimore, Maryland, to "My dear Sir," n.p., 11 February 1891., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Is not acquainted with any of the aforementioned Greek works.
    - W[illia]m B. Giles, Council Chamber, Richmond, Virginia, to The Governor of Kentucky, [Joseph Desha], 24 April 1827., 1 page. LS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Requests the return of Reuben Smith, now resident in Perry County, Kentucky, a fugitive from justice in Virginia.
    - Steph[e]n Girard, Philad[elphia, Pennsylvania], to Moses Myers, Norfolk, [Virginia], 15 August 1791., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Hopes Myers has taken possession of Girard's land on the Eastern Shore and procured a purchaser. Gives prices of various commodities.
    - Ellen Glasgow, New York, New York, to Annie [Mrs. F. T. Clark?], Norfolk, Virginia, 20 February 1912., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Mentions coming for a visit, needing "absolute quiet" for a week or two; hopes the buttercups will be blooming in Williamsburg before long.
    - J. B. Gordon, Peoria, Illinois, to E. St. John, n.p., 21 January 1898., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Requests that a family annual for 1898 be sent to him at his home in Atlanta.
    - Horace Greeley, New York, [New York], to James H. Plott, House of Rep[resentative]s, Washington, D.C., 31 November 1870., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Comments on an article which provoked General Imboden, published in the Virginia State Journal.
    - Nath[anie]l Greene, Boston, [Massachusetts], to Sam[ue]l Storke, London, [England], 21 May 1784., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Is sending barrels of rice to meet a debt. Requests Storke to return balance in cash.
    - Hugh B. Grigsby, Roanoke Bridge, [Virginia], to Francis N. Watkins, Farmville, Virginia, 15 October 1852., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Acknowledges receipt of a genealogy of the Watkins family and comments on members of the Watkins and Morton families.
    - List signed by Al[exander] Hamilton, 23 July 1789., 1 page. DS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      List of land and houses at Port Tobacco, Piscataway and Benedict, in Prince Georges and Charles counties, Maryland, belonging to James Gordon and others, surviving partners of John Glassford & Co., on 31 December 1777, which was confiscated and sold as British property.
    - H. Hamlin, Portland, [Maine], to Ellie [?], n.p., 5 September [18]57., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Newsy note describing a visit with old friends and a trip to Paris, [France] made by Eliza.
    - M. A. Hanna, United States Senate, Washington, D.C., to [?] Bowden, n.p., 24 March [18]98., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Thank you for the oysters which were "very fine".
    - John M. Harlan, Washington, D.C., to Rob[er]t M. Hughes, n.p., 23 June 1896., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Concerning invitation of the bar Association and his choice of topic for a speech.
    - Benj[amin] Harrison, Ch[arle]s City[County, Virginia], to "The Worshipful Court of York County.", 3 August 1769., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Concerns land sold by him to Capt. William Evans, for which a receipt was delivered to Harrison's overseer, Edmund Borrom, and the bond for which was transferred to James Eason. Also concerns wheat bought by Evans and delivered to John Goodrich's vessel.
    - Card bearing Benj[amin] Harrison's signature, 8 January 1894., 1 page. ACS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    - R.B. Hayes, Fremont, Ohio, to F.L. Taylor, Lynchburg, [Virginia], 24 January 1885., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Apologizes for a misunderstanding dealing with an invitation to attend a meeting of the Trustees of the State Fund for the Education of Freedmen.
    - Answer of Patrick Henry Defendant to the Bill of Complaint exhibited against him and others by Thomas Lomax in Augusta County, [Virginia], Court. Signed by P[atrick] Henry, 22 June 1781., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    - A.P. Hill, H[ea]d Q[uartere]r[s] 3 Comp., [n.p.], to Georgie [?], n.p., 19 March 1864., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Squelches rumor of review because of the difficulties of long marching; family news.
    - James P. Holcombe, Richmond, [Virginia], to "My Dear Sir," n.p., 3 July 1862. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Concerning a discussion with the Secretary of War about a military arrangement for the gratification of the people of the Southwest; arm and men of the Confederate government; and the President [Jefferson Davis].
    - O. W. Holmes, n.p. to [?], 25 December 1863., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Regrets that he must cancel a lecturing engagement at Buffalo, New York because of illness.
    - Tho[ma]s Hood, Adelphi, [?], to J. Britton, n.p., no date., 1 page. AL. (Box-folder 2:2)
    - Jos[eph] Hopkinson, Philad[elphia, Pennsylvania] to Rev. William A. [sic] [Buell] Sprague, West Springfield, Massachusetts, 13 November 1828., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      Concerning request for autographs of famous men, from letters of Hopkinson's father.
    - Ro[bert] R. Howison, Richmond, Virginia, to Col. W[illia]m E. Peters, Wytheville, Virginia, 8 August 1862., 1 page. LS. (Box-folder 2:2)
      At the suggestion of R.W. Hughes, writes to request a memorandum regarding the campaign of Gen. [John B.] Floyd in Western Virginia in 1861 for a history of the war he is preparing.
  - Autograph Collection, J-M, 1755-1900., 26 items. (Box-folder 2:3)
    - Th[omas] Jefferson, Monticello, [Virginia], to Albert Gallatin, Paris, [France], 16 March [18]17., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Concerning a letter of introduction for William C. Preston.
    - Joseph Johnson, Charleston, [West Virginia], to H[enr]y B. Dawson, n.p., 13 August 1859., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Sends an [enclosed] account of "The Battle of Mobley's Meeting House" South Carolina in June 1780.
    - R[ic]h[ard] M. Johnson, Senate Chamber, [Washington, D.C.], to W[illia]m H. Crawford, Sec. of the Treasury, [Washington, D.C.], 10 December 1823., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Recommends Samuel Myers of Richmond for a position in the Treasury Department.
    - Mary Johnston, Williamsburg, Virginia, to "My Dear Cousin," n.p., 25 April n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Concerning the Nicholson-Burwell courtship as a possible topic of a novel or story.
    - J[ohn] W[illia]m Jones, Richmond, Virginia, to his cousin, Ella [?], n.p., 10 February 1900., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Acknowledges receipt of an autograph book for his use. Will be able to add to her collection.
    - Kalakua, Honolulu, [Hawaii], to William Nevens Armstrong, New York, [New York], 9 February 1878., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Concerns a means of conserving water in Hawaii by the use of pumps.
    - James Kent, New York, [New York], to Rev[eren]d Doctor [William B.] Sprague, Albany, [New York], 5 April 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Acknowledges receipt of Sprague's address on George Washington.
    - H. Knox, Thomastown, Lincoln County, [Maine], to Samuel G. Perkins, Boston, Suffolk County, [Massachusetts], 27 November 1805., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Recognizance of debt.
    - Gen[era]l Henry Lee, Alex[andri]a, [Virginia], to "Dear Sir," n.p., 28 June [17]87., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Concerning Congress and mention of their circular letter relative to the treaty with Britain.
    - Benjamin W[atkins] Leigh, Richmond, [Virginia], to Francis N. Watkins, n.p., 24 April 1840., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Gives genealogy information of the Watkins family.
    - Commission of Samuel C. Waite to Second Lieutenant of Light Infantry in the 108th Regiment Virginia Militia. Signed by John Letcher, Governor, 18 June 1861., 1 page. DS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      ADS on verso, 28 June 1861, certifying that Waite took requisite oaths in Greenbrier County, [Virginia] before Charles R. Hines, Justice of the Peace. 1 page. Also ADS on verso, 15 September 1861, by Sam[ue]l C. Waite, resigning his commission as Sr. 2nd Lieutenant in Company G of the 22nd Regiment Virginia Volunteers. 1 page.
    - A. Lewis, Green Plains, [Virginia?], to [?], 20 April 1796., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Concerning Mr. Elijah McClanahan and his business contract, and Lewis' willingness to serve as an agent in Indian Affairs preferably with the Chickasaws and the Creeks.
    - Francis Lieber, Columbia, South Carolina, to [?], 11 January 1850., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Requests information about a revision of the Virginia's statutes, published in 1848. Desires to send a copy to a German jurist and statesman.
    - Certificate of John A. Little of Massachusetts, as Consul of the United States, Barcelona, [Spain], signed by President Abraham Lincoln, 21 June 1861., 1 page. PDS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Also signed by Secretary of State, William H. Seward. See Medium Oversize File.
    - Henry W. Longfellow, Cambridge, [Massachusetts], to "Dear Madam," n.p., 10 November 1863., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Is sending another photograph.
    - Henry W. Longfellow, Cambridge, [Massachusetts], to Mr. L. Reich, New York, New York, 13 March 1882. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Acknowledges receipt of a case of wine. [This is not the last letter written by Henry Wadsworth Longfellow. See Samuel Longfellow, ed., Life of Henry Wadsworth Longfellow with extracts from his journals and correspondence, Boston, 1886, Vol. II, p.471]
    - Geo[rge] B. McClellan, 1858., 1 item. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Signature.
    - A legal document substituting executors under a will of James Patton, 26 November 1755., 1 page. Cy of ADS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Signed by J[ohn] Madison[father of a Bishop James Madison].
    - J. Marshall, for Anthony Warwick of Liverpool, Great Britain, in United States Middle Circuit District of Virginia, [ca. 1800]., 3 pages. ADS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Bill of complaint in suit against James Kennedy, Jr., and James Cavan, late merchants of Alexandria, Virginia, for debt.
      ANS on verso, n.d., giving findings of the jury for the plaintiff, [Warwick], signed by Bernard Markham. 1 page.
    - J. Y. Mason, Paris, [France], to Gov. Henry A. Wise, Richmond, Virginia, 28 January 1857., 10 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Concerning Mason's position as minister to France for the U.S., Mr. Buchanan's election, and Mason's "abrupt, voluntary retirement" from the position; negotiations concerning maritime rights; and deep friendship with Wise.
    - Theobald Mathew, Cork, [Ireland], to [?] Fox, n.p., 25 April 1847., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Acknowledges contribution to assist the Irish during the Famine.
    - S. K. Watkins, Chapel Hill, [North Carolina], to Bishop [William] Meade, n.p., 29 February 1860., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Concerns genealogy of the Watkins family.
      Including ALS from William Meade, Mellwood, Clark Co., Virginia, to [Francis Watkins?], n.p., 13 March [18]60, concerning the forwarding of the letter.
    - B. B. Minor, Richmond, [Virginia], to Miss Ella M. Thomas, City [Richmond, Virginia], 25 January 1900., 1 page. ACS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Concerning Thomas and Robert Sully, and the latter's studio in Richmond.
    - D. L. Moody, no date., 1 item. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Pass to admit two to the First Pres[byterian] Church all the month of March. Signature.
    - F. L. Moore, Camp Defiance, to L[eroy] P[ope] Walker, n.p., 3 October 1861., 2 pages. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Requests transfer from Co. C, 13th Regt., Georgia Volunteers. Approved by John L. Moore, Capt., Co. C. 13th Regt., Georgia Volunteers, and by Walton Ector, Col., 13th Regt., Georgia Volunteers.
    - Thomas Moore, n.p., to J. Taylor, "Sun" Office, Strand, [London, England], no date., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
      Sends a newspaper notice to be published concerning a translation of Lucien Bonaparte's poem.
  - Autograph Collection, P-T, 1753-1924., 26 items. (Box-folder 2:4)
    - Alton B. Parker, Rosemount, Esopus, New York, to B. B. Minor, 7 November 1904., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Acknowledges letter written by Minor.
    - "Thos. F. Pendel. November 3 1864. December 17 1900." Signature, no date., 1 item. PCS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Written on back of visiting card of Miss Elizabeth Whiting Conrad.
    - Frank[lin] Pierce, Lowell, [Massachusetts], to Dr. [?] Boutelle, Coast Survey, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 27 June 1848., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Desires Dr. Boutelle's presence when the suit of Hadley vs. Dodges and Jones is tried.
    - Puizot, n.p. to the President of the College Louis the Great, n.p., 9 June n.y., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Renewing the request that M. Peraud, Master of studies, bring Favie to Puizot's home during the vacation. In French. Includes translation.
    - Sam[uel] J. Randall, Berwyn, Chester Co., Pennsylvania, to Col. S. Bassett French, n.p., 4 September 1879., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Speaks of a certain "matter" between them.
    - Geo[rge] W. Randolph, Richmond, [Virginia], to R. G. H. Theon, n.p., 17 April 1857., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Concerns proceedings in two suits: Boyd's Admr. vs. The City Savings Bank, and Boyd's Admr. vs. Dimmock & Co.
    - J. R. of Roanoke, Washington, [D.C.], to "Dear Sir," n.p., 17 January 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Concerns proceedings in Congress.
    - Certificate permitting John Skinner to practice as an attorney in James City County, Virginia, 13 October [1757]., 1 page. Ph of DS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Signed by Peyton Randolphe, J. Power, and G[eorge] Wythe.
    - Geo[rge] Read, New] Castle, [Delaware], to Gunning Bedford, n.p., 17 March 1780., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Sends order to be entered in records of case of John Moore, Administrator of Lydia Moore, deceased, vs. John Ball, referring the matters in variance to arbitration by Charles Williams, John Reece, James Boggs, all of Mill-Creek Hundred [Delaware]. Read is attorney for the plaintiff who lives in Virginia.
    - Wyndham Robertson, "The Meadows," Abingdon, [Virginia], to [?] Chamberlayne, n.p., 30 September 1878., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Asks name of a contributor on the subject of currency.
    - W.S. Rosecrans, House of Representatives, Washington, D.C., to Forrester L. Taylor, Lynchburg, Virginia, 21 January 1885., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Note regarding Losing's Pictorial History of the U.S.
    - Jo[h]n G. Saxe, Brooklyn, New York, to W.S. Perry, n.p., 27 May [18]74., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
      Thanks Perry for the letter and the program; suggests that following "scholarly etiquette," L. D. be added after his [Saxe's] name since he has received an honorary degree.